Jerson Martínez

DevOps Engineer

Managua, Nicaragua (CST) (+505) 89630866 <u>jersonmartinezsm@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jersonmartinezsm/</u> <u>https://github.com/jersonmartinez</u>

A little about me, I consider myself a Kaizeneta, founder of Crashell and principal developer of GNet. Passionate about DevOps culture and everything around Automation processes with 2+ years of experience in this field, working with Cloud Providers such as AWS and Azure. In addition to working with technologies such as Git, Vagrant, Docker, Ansible, Grafana, Podman and with 5+ years of experience working with scripting languages such as Windows Batch, Linux Bash and PowerShell. With 5+ years of experience, I also stand out as a Full-Stack Web Developer, with a Tech Stack such as HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, Python and Golang. Adaptable to collective intelligence. Soccer and chess fan.

EXPERIENCE

Hotaka iKhodi

DevOps Engineer — September, 2020 - Present

- I have reduced 60% of the time in performing and verifying database backups in SQL RDS through automated executions in Bash. In addition, to automate the launching of new infrastructures.
- With 2+ years of experience, I have been working directly with my supervisor on analytics proposals to perform different automation work with AWS Lambda and Azure DevOps.
- I have been growing in the use of IaC technologies, NoSQL databases and resource observability.

Tech Stack: AWS EC2, RDS, CloudFront, Route53, Grafana, Filebeat, Telegraf, ELK, Bash, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, etc.

Elite Online Media

Full-Stack Developer — January, 2019 - September, 2020

- In terms of productivity, I improved by 60% the way of sharing code, implementing Git and GitHub, creating the collaborative work model for software design and development teams. In addition, from this milestone, I gave way to remote work. Thanks to the collaborations I was awarded the best worker of the year 2019.
- I fixed security issues on servers hosting hundreds of web projects, automating the correction of a malware
 injection and keeping hundreds of our clients' websites from being corrupted or down.
- More than 4 years of experience in web development, I was able to provide different proposals to improve the development of projects, such as being the creator of the main core of the apps, written in pure PHP.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, PHP, AJAX, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Docker, and digital Marketing tools.

PROJECTS

Crashell - www.crashell.com - 2020

• A platform where services are offered and content is shared around the DevOps culture, a project of which I am the founder. I have shared content as a writer, as well as complete technology courses and currently in the process of publishing my first book on Git and GitHub towards a DevOps culture.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: <u>Advanced:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Bash, PowerShell; <u>Intermediate:</u> Python; <u>Basic:</u> Golang. **Tools:** <u>Advanced:</u> Git, GitHub, Vagrant, Docker, Podman; <u>Intermediate:</u> Ansible, Grafana, ELK Stack, Amazon Web Services; <u>Basic:</u> Ansible Molecule, Kubernetes, Terraform, Microsoft Azure, Jenkins, Circle CI, Travis CI, RabbitMQ.

Methodologies: Advanced: Kanban; Intermediate: Scrum; Basic: Project Management.

Database: Advanced: MySQL - MariaDB, PostgreSQL; Intermediate: SQL Server; Basic: MongoDB, Redis.

Languages: English, B1; Spanish, Native.

EDUCATION

UNAN – Leon, Nicaragua. Telematics Engineer, Jan 2013 - Dec 2017

• Thesis: GNet, Computer Network Management Web System. Obtaining an excellent score of 100.

OpenWebinars - Online technologies courses, Dec 2017 - Present

• I have earned over 50 certifications in programming, software development, infrastructure management, team management and leadership.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals - Microsoft. 2022.

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon. 2021.

Professional Docker DevOps - OpenWebinars. 2018 - 2019.